終局を始める前に
Before the finale begins, before we reach the end,
終極に至る前に
I'm sure you, my dear readers, have not forgotten
開示しなければならない物語が
もうひとつだけ残されていることを
that there is a story left that I must disclose to you.
読者諸兄(しょけい)もまさか忘れてはいないだろう
白状すれば 僕としては忘れていて欲しかったところだし
Frankly, I would have wanted you to forget,
and even more so, would have wanted to forget it myself.
それ以上に忘れていたかったところなのだが
Keeping it undisclosed,
secretly and sorrowfully
pretending it had never happened,
I would've liked to end this story about me.
そうは問屋(とんや)が卸(おろ)しませんよ 阿良々木先輩
You won't get away so easily, Araragi.
Trying to hide something from me is foolish.
私の前で隠し事をしようだなんて
そんな無謀はおよしください
私は嘘や誤魔化しの天敵です
I am the nemesis of lies and deception.
先延ばしや後回しの捕食者です
I am the predator of delay and postponement.
卓越した詐欺師 貝木(かいき)泥舟(でいしゅう)の顛末を
あなただって知らないわけじゃあないでしょう?
You should be aware of what befell Kaiki Deishuu, the great fraud.
If you don't wish to end up like him, please tell your story.
ああなりたくないのであれば 語ってくださいよ
Tell the story you've been so adamant to keep hidden until now.
あなたが頑(かたく)なに これまでひた隠しにしてきた
あのときの話を
I could tell from looking at her that she already knew exactly of the events being referred to,
その様子を見る限りにおいて 彼女は
あのときの出来事について既に知り尽くしているようにも思えたが
そう問うたとしても 空とぼけるだけだろう
but had I confronted her with such a suspicion, she simply would have feigned ignorance.
私は何も知りませんよ
I know nothing.
You're the one who knows.
あなたが知っているんです 阿良々木先輩
その通り
She is right.
I know.
僕は知っている
とてもよく知っている
I know very well what happened.
知っているからこそ 隠したかったのだが
And precisely because I know, I wished to hide it.
Reference
知っているからには 語らねばならない
And likewise because I know, I have to tell it.
長い話になるぜ と僕は言う
This story will take a while, I said.
構いませんとも
I don't mind.
あれは 忍野扇が転校してくる
二ヵ月以上前のハプニングである
This story describes les événements of more than two months prior to Ougi transferring into our school.
夏休みが終わり 二学期が始まった直後
Summer break was over,
and the second term had just begun.
Emergency Button
His link to the vampire had been severed,
Naoetsu Private High School
吸血鬼とのペアリングが切られ およそ半年振りに
and for the first time in about half a year,
Araragi Koyomi experienced being more or less human again.
ほぼ生身の "人間" を体感している阿良々木暦が
He didn't go to school.
学校にも行かず
家にも帰らず
He didn't go home.
かつて専門家 忍野メメが寝床とした
学習塾跡の廃ビルのいち教室で
He was hiding in one of the classrooms in the decrepit
cram school that the specialist Oshino Meme had used
時間をもてあますように
身を潜(ひそ)めている場面から
to sleep in as though he had all the time in the world.
Tonight, 9:00 O'clock
Alone, Second Floor
Come To The Classroom
There's something
I want to ask you
Here the story begins,
物語は始まる
物語は終わる
and here the story ends
そして "彼" の人生も
together with the life of another.
続き続けた "彼" の人生も
ようやく終わる
The life of one that time had tested in vain.
End Story
Shinobu Mail
Shinobu Mail Part One
End Story
阿良々木先輩
Araragi!
おっひざー!
Long time no see!
Long time no knee!
あげるにしても
もっとスタイリッシュな悲鳴をあげたいものだった
Having already screamed,
I only wished it had been more chic.
車に轢(ひ)かれた蛙(かえる) みたいな悲鳴では
あまりに格好がつかない
Screaming like a frog run over
by a car is not particularly cool.
まあ 後輩に 出会いがしらに膝蹴りを食らった時点で
格好良さなんてまるっきり望むべくもないんだが
Well, perhaps it's out of line to hope for a cool way of getting kneed in the face.
おっと さすがは一流の阿良々木先輩
Nice one, Araragi.
早速 出会いがしらと膝頭(ひざがしら)をかけてくるとは
Immediately making a pun on getting kneed in times of need is impressive.
これは一本取られたな
This round goes to you.
もっとも阿良々木先輩
However, Araragi.
恐縮ながら言わせていただけるのであれば 私は膝頭という言いかたよりも
膝小僧(こぞう)という言いかたのほうが好きだ
Permit me to say this, but I prefer the word patella over the word kneecap.
美少年を二人 自分の膝に住まわせていると思うと
私はほんの少しだけ 幸せになれる
It's just one letter away from paella, and thinking something hot and Spanish is inside me makes me happy.
幸せって言葉をそんな風に使うな
You insult the word happiness.
あとなんで美少年限定なんだよ
Why must you make it so dirty?
美少年というか イメージ的にはお稚児(ちご)さんなのだ
Better yet would be knee chaps instead of kneecaps.
誰しも膝にお稚児さんを住まわせていると思うと
世の中が少しだけ 豊かに見えないか?
Doesn't the world seem richer if you think everyone has two little boys inside them?
豊かって言葉もそんな風に使うな
You insult the word rich!
僕の膝にはお稚児さんはいねえよ
I don't have little boys inside me!
つーか
Anyway.
一番の突っ込みどころは お前が先輩である僕を蹴ったことを
まだ一言も謝っていないということだ
My main criticism should probably be that you haven't apologized for kicking your senior.
謝る?
Apologize?
何を言っておるのだ
Don't be silly.
私こと忠実なる後輩 神原駿河は
いまや阿良々木先輩の肉体の一部のようなものではないか
Is my loyalty not such that I should be considered a part of your body?
Who would apologize to themselves for resting their cheek on their own knee?
自分の膝がほっぺたに当たったからといって
人は自分に謝ったりしないだろう
That only sounds smart until you actually think about it!
立て板に水の酷い理屈だな!
To be honest, I know that you regenerate very quickly,
まあ正直 阿良々木先輩は回復力が高いから
あれくらいのニアミスは別に謝らなくてもいいかなと思っているのはある
so I felt that a near-miss like that was no big deal.
正直に言えばなんでも許されると思うなよ!
Honesty doesn't excuse everything!
ちょっと歯ァ砕(くだ)けてんじゃねえか
Look, you knocked out a tooth...
どうした阿良々木先輩
What's wrong, Araragi?
急にそんな風に
私のプロポーションをじろじろ見たりして
You seem interested in my proportions.
プロポーションを見てるんじゃない
I wasn't checking out your proportions.
What?
プロポーションを見ずに私の何を見るのだ?
If you weren't checking them out, why else would you look at me?
私にはプロポーションくらいしか見るべきところはないだろう
Is that not the best thing about me?
謎の卑屈(ひくつ)さを発揮するな
直江津高校のスター
Stop with the sudden humility!
You're Naoetsu High School's best athlete.
そんなじろじろ見なくとも
心配は無用だ 阿良々木先輩
You don't have to look at me with such concern, Araragi.
心配?
Concern?
僕がお前の何を心配してるって言うんだよ
Is there something I should be concerned about?
Don't play dumb.
またまたとぼけちゃって
You're such a gentleman, Araragi.
気遣いの人だものな 阿良々木先輩は
But don't worry. You can trust your junior some more.
だがあなたはもう少し あなたの後輩を信用してよい
大丈夫
No worries.
I left the bra home.
ちゃんとブラは外してきた
Bra
Now I'm starting to be concerned!
僕はお前が本気で心配だよ!
Bra
No Bra
Perverted
Girl
My hoodie is rather thick,
so you probably can't tell by looking at me,
如何(いかん)せんジャージの生地が分厚いので
見た目ではわからないかもしれないが
この神原駿河 阿良々木先輩に嘘はつかない
but I wouldn't lie to you, Araragi!
I'm wearing this hoodie over bare skin.
上半身に限って言うなら
今の私は素肌にジャージだ
And what about the lower half?
下半身どうなってんだよ
不安だよ
I'm worried.
Huh?
But, I mean... Calling me out to this place,
at this hour, can only mean one thing, right?
でもでも こんな時間に こんな場所に
私を呼び出したっていうのは そういうことだろう?
One thing?
そういうこと?
What thing?
どういうことだよ
I thought you had finally decided to take my virginity.
ついに阿良々木先輩が
私の純潔を貰(もら)ってくれる気になった ということだろう?
Of course not!
だろわねえよ!
Tonight, 9:00 O'clock
Alone, Second Floor
Come To The Classroom
There's something
I want to ask you
Tonight, 9:00 O'clock
Alone, Second Floor
Come To The Classroom
There's something
I want to ask you
Look, Araragi.
しかし それでも阿良々木先輩
Asking a girl—a woman—to come alone, at night,
to a place away from prying eyes using a suggestive text
女の子を つまり女子を 夜に 単身 人気(ひとけ)のない場所に
意味深なメールで呼び出したという時点で
No Entry
Private Property
Beware
Danger
cannot be taken many different ways.
そういう風に受け取られても
それは仕方のないことではないのか?
Alone, Second
Come To
Besides, Araragi.
それに阿良々木先輩
I accidentally went to the third floor out of excitement when I got here,
さっき私は 勢い余って
二階ではなく三階の教室に行ってしまったのだが
and there was a bed on one of the tables.
机で作られたベッドが用意されていたぞ?
あれは阿良々木先輩が用意したものではないのか?
Didn't you put it there?
え? それは本当に心当たりがないんだが...
What? No, I really have no idea.
A bed?
ベッド?
You always play dumb.
またまたとぼけちゃって
またまたって言われても
Always, huh? I'm not really that type of character.
別に僕 とぼける系のキャラじゃないんだけど
We can call it a fait accompli marriage,
and you could enjoy my virginity right here and now.
既成事実婚ということで もうこの際
阿良々木先輩は私の純潔を貰っちゃっていいんじゃないだろうか
だからだろわねえよ
I told you I won't.
What's a fait accompli marriage, anyway?
If anything, it's fait inaccompli
Back to the subject!
So, about why I asked you to come here.
えっと... それで
お前を呼び出した用件なのだが
Tonight, 9:00 O'clock
Alone, Second Floor
Come To The Classroom
There's something
I want to ask you
Tonight, 9:00 O'clock
Alone, Second Floor
Come To The Classroom
There's something
I want to ask you
ふむ 何か訊(き)きたいことがあるとのことだったな?
You wanted to ask me something, if I remember correctly.
ああ そうだ
Yeah.
てっきりその訊きたいことというのが
私の純潔に対する質問なのだと思っていたが
I was thoroughly convinced that your questions
concerned my virginity, but I guess I jumped the gun.
それはどうやら早とちりだったらしい
早い遅いの問題じゃなく
とちり通しだよお前は
You did, and I hope you won't be
jumping any guns for a while longer.
僕がお前にそんな質問をする機会は
いつまでも来ない
I'd never ask you about that.
訊きたいことっていうのは... つまり
What I want to ask you about is...
お前に協力して欲しいことがあるんだけれど
Well, I want you to help me with something.
手伝ってくれるかってことなんだ
I want to ask you whether you'll help me.
本音を言うと この件
僕はお前には断って欲しいと思っているんだが
To be honest, I'd rather you refused me.
Of course I accept!
断るわけがないな!
この神原駿河が 阿良々木先輩からの要請に応えないなど
あるはずがない!
How could I, Kanbaru Suruga,
ever refuse your requests, Araragi?
たとえ天地が引っ繰り返ることがあろうともだ!
Pigs would sooner fly through a frozen hell!
You see, it's not really my own request.
まあ 必ずしも僕の要請ってわけじゃないんだが
I'm just the intermediary.
僕はあくまで仲介であって
しかも 協力して欲しいことの内容も
詳しくは知らないって言うか
Besides, I don't really know myself what you'd be helping with.
You don't know?
知らない?
No, not at all.
うん 何にも知らない
I was probably never told on purpose.
So if you refused me here, that would be the end of it.
だから お前がここで断ってくれたら
それでこの話がおしまいになるから
そっちのほうがいい
I would prefer that.
Of course, should you decide to help, I would do my utmost to protect your body from injury.
もちろん お前があくまで手伝ってくれるっていうのであれば
お前の身に危険が及ばないよう 僕は全力を尽くすつもりだけれど
ははは 私の身など
阿良々木先輩が気にする必要はないのだ
You don't have to worry about my body.
それでもどうしても気になると言うのであれば
身の体積のほんの一部
If you want to ponder my body,
then you're welcome to ponder the volume of my breasts.
即(すなわ)ち
おっぱいの辺りのことだけを考えてくれていればよい
The hell I will!
よいわけあるか
That I have come running to this cram school against all odds should be enough answer for you, Araragi.
もしも阿良々木先輩の訊きたいことがそれならば
私が万難を排してこの学習塾に駆けつけたことが 既に答だとは思わないか?
うん まあ... そうだな
Uh, I guess.
I was overwhelmed by the desire to serve your every need.
阿良々木先輩にご奉仕(ほうし)したくてしたくて
しょうがない私なのだ
今夜は読みたかった本があったというのに
There was a book I wanted to read this evening,
阿良々木先輩のためにわざわざ来てやったのだぞ?
but I came here just for you.
A book you wanted to read?
読みたかった本って
I'm competing with a book now?
先輩の優先順位が本と競ってるじゃないか
So, Kanbaru.
じゃあ神原
今夜はいったい何を読むつもりだったんだ?
What did you want to read tonight?
Something by Yamamoto Shuugorou of course!
山本(やまもと)周五郎(しゅうごろう)先生に決まっておろう
Which one by him?
ちなみに山本周五郎の何を読んでるんだよ
お前が読んでる本なら僕も読みたい
If you like it, I want to read it too.
だったらお勧めのＢＬ小説もたくさんあるのだが
Oh, if that's the case, I have some boy love novels to recommend!
まずは山本周五郎からにしてくれ
Let's start with Yamamoto Shuugorou.
そうか じゃあ
Okay. Let's see.
"美少女一番乗り"と言うのだが
It's called "First at the Maiden."
Liar!
嘘をつけ!
As if the renowned Yamamoto Shuugorou would choose a title like that!
山本周五郎先生がそんなタイトルの本を書くか!
いや でも実際に出ているんだから仕方ないだろう
But it really exists... What are you going to do?
まあ現状 品切れ重版未定状態ではあるが
I guess it's actually out of print with no second edition in sight, though.
Back to the subject!
All right, Kanbaru.
さて 神原
頼みごとなんだが
What I was going to ask you...
I'm sorry to spring this on you, but would you come with me?
じゃあ 早速で悪いんだが
ちょっと一緒に来てくれるか
ん? なんだ
Huh?
ここに用事があるわけじゃないのか?
I thought everything was going to go down here.
ああ ここは単なるお前との待ち合わせ場所だよ
No, I only meant to meet you here.
へえ... だったら別に
家で待ち合わせてもよかっただろうに
So... Why didn't we meet at home, then?
Huh? Why did I make this our meeting point, anyway?
あれ なんで僕は
この学習塾跡を待ち合わせ場所に指定したんだっけ?
確か...
I think...
まあ 構わん
Well, I don't mind.
仔細(しさい)は問わない
I won't pry.
どこにでも行こう
Let's go wherever you want.
大丈夫
I'll be fine.
遺書はもう書いてきた
I wrote my will.
怖いことすんな!
That's depressing!
まあ 今からそんな身構えなくとも 神原
You don't have to get so worked up, Kanbaru.
これから行くのもまた ただの待ち合わせ場所だよ
We're just heading to a different meeting point now.
A rendezvous point...
合流地点って言うのか...
Basically, I want to introduce you to someone.
お前に会わせたい人がいるんだ
Oh my, look at you.
おやおや まったく困った人だ
Whom did you try to impress and how?
誰に対してどんな見栄を張ったんだ?
With grades? Contacts? Popularity?
成績か人間関係か? モテ度か?
No. I don't want you to back up my story.
違う
合わせたい話があるんじゃない
会わせたい人がいるんだ
I just want you to meet someone.
お前を紹介して欲しいって言われてて
They said they wanted to meet you.
ふうん まあいいや
All righty.
阿良々木先輩の言うことなら
まず間違いあるまい
I'm sure what you say is all fine.
I feel like you'd be better off trusting me about half as much as you do.
できれば僕に対する信頼度を半分くらいに減らして欲しいのだが
But don't worry.
でも 大丈夫だ
少なくとも男子や女子が お前に告白するとか
そういう紹介とか仲介とかじゃないから
What I know for sure is that some boy or girl
won't confess their love for you this evening.
別にそういう紹介でも構わないぞ?
I wouldn't mind that, anyway.
普通に断るし
I'd just turn them down.
If you go and say, "Alas, it was me!"
then of course things are different.
"紹介したい人は...僕でした!"みたいな落ちならば
無論 話は別だが
隙を見ては僕と付き合おうとするな
Don't try to seize every opportunity to go out with me.
どんな肉食系だよ
How can you be so hell-bent on carnal relations?
いや 付き合おうとはしていない
But I don't want to go out with you.
肉体関係だけでいい
Just the carnal part is enough.
肉食系だけに 一方的に捕食したい
A carnal carnivore needs their catch.
I'm getting goose bumps.
ぞっとするぜ
I don't believe in emotional attachment!
私は精神的な繋(つな)がりなど信じない
お前の人生に一体なにがあった
What on Earth happened in your life?
つーか お前一体何を考えて生きてるんだよ
And by what do you live it?
If it looks to you like I think about life, you should see an optometrist.
私が何かを考えているように見えるんだったら
病院に行ったほうがよいな
閑話休題
Back to the subject!
Okey-dokey, Araragi.
オーキードーキー 阿良々木先輩
委細承知
I have grasped the details.
では参ろうではないか
Let us venture forth.
どこだかわからない場所に
誰だかわからない人に会いに!
Let us go to meet someone I don't know somewhere I don't know!
You can be pretty amazing.
やっぱすげえな お前...
Deleaveture!
でっぱつだ!
Huh? Who's that? Another visitor?
ん? なんだ 来客か?
這入っていいぞ
Come in!
え? 阿良々木先輩の知り合いが来たんじゃないのか?
Isn't that some acquaintance of yours?
私の他にも誰かを呼んでいたということではないのか?
I thought you had called someone else here beside me.
いや 僕が呼んだのはお前だけで
No, I only called you...
か 神原っ
K-Kanbaru—
Take cover, Araragi!
阿良々木先輩 伏せてろ!
Empty
Araragi, this isn't just empty... It's an empty shell.
阿良々木先輩 空と言うより
殻(から)だったぞ
Shell
There was no resistance at all.
手ごたえがなさ過ぎだ
空振りしたかと思ったくらいだ
I felt like I hit the empty air.
なんなのだ あれは?
What is that?
阿良々木先輩の友達か?
A friend of yours?
僕に鎧の友達はいねえよ
None of my friends is a suit of armor.
ではどんな友達がいるのだろう
Then what sort of friends do you have?
あれ...
Huh?
Well, well...
どうした神原
What's wrong, Kanbaru?
いや 一式揃った甲冑だと思っていたのだが
よく見たら 足りないな
Oh, I just... thought it was a full suit of armor,
but now that I look at it carefully, it's missing something.
足りない?
Missing?
Yeah. You see, we have five or six suits of armor at home too,
うん ほら 私の家にも甲冑は五
六個あるんだけれど
それと比べてみると あの鎧武者には
肝心のものがない
and compared to them, I feel like this one is missing something vital.
To me it didn't seem like something was missing.
でも 僕が見る限り
足りない部品なんかなかったように思うけれど
ああそうだ 神原
Oh, Kanbaru.
甲冑への造詣(ぞうけい)があるって言うんだったら
あれをもう一回 組み直してみてくれるか?
Since you have such intimate knowledge of armor sets, could you assemble it again?
What, me?
え? 私がか?
Well, I don't know how to assemble it.
だって僕には甲冑の組み立てかたと
かわからないもん
じゃあ私が指示するから
阿良々木先輩が組み立てたらどうだろう
How about I tell you what to do and you do it?
You know no hesitation when it comes to using your senior, huh?
先輩を使うことに躊躇(ちゅうちょ)がないよな お前は
まあいいけど
Well, all right.
I will demonstrate to you that I can do more than lie on the floor and shield my head!
僕がただ 言われるがままに
うつ伏せになっているだけの男ではないところを見せてやろう
うつ伏せだけじゃなく
仰向(あおむ)けにもなれるところを
I can also look up!
I don't really want the person I respect to look up at me.
尊敬する先輩が仰向けになっているところこそ
見たくないが
でも なぜ組み立て直す必要があるのだ?
But why do you want to have it assembled anyway?
Look, maybe it moves again if we reassemble it.
いや 組み立てたら
ひょっとしたらまた動き出すかもしれないじゃないか
What this armor lacks
この甲冑に足りないもの
is...
それは
Stand back, Araragi!
下がっていろ 阿良々木先輩!
Fist
Punch
Touch
Body
Hit
Abdomen
Push
Left
Strike
Hand
Patch
Power
Energy Drain
Touch
Left
Monkey
Rain
Pain
Punch
Jaw
Fist
Energy Drain
Hit
Touch
Monkey
Neck
Fly
Throat
Hit
Pain
Kanbaru!
神原!?
Stay there!
く 来るな!
え...?
いや なんかこいつ
Isn't he
getting tougher?
だんだん頑丈になってないか
あ—
A—
Araragi...
阿良々木先輩
Run away.
逃げろ
That was the one order I could not obey.
だんだん頑丈(がんじょう)になる鎧武者
The armor became gradually tougher.
対照的に 神原がだんだん弱っていることに
僕は気付いていなかった
And, conversely, I hadn't realized
Kanbaru became gradually weaker.
Her first punch struck his torso.
最初に胴体に一撃を入れ
Another punch struck his chin,
また一撃を入れ 顎を殴ったところで
and she went down to one knee afterwards.
彼女は片膝をついた
あの時点で
どうして神原がくずおれたのか不思議だったが
I thought it strange that she lost strength there,
but I only understood once I saw her drop to the ground right after her tackle.
タックルでしがみついた直後に倒れた彼女を見て
僕は得心(とくしん)した
エナジードレイン
Energy drain.
Energy Drain
なんで?
Why?
どうして古風な 時代錯誤な鎧武者が
吸血鬼さながらのエナジードレインを使ってくる
Why does this old, anachronistic armor use the energy drain of vampires?
What is that?
なんなんだ あいつは?
What's wrong with you?
な なんなんだ お前
Why are you here?
なんのつもりだ
What do you have against us?
僕達に何の恨みがある
Why are you doing this?
どうしてこんなことをするんだ
Stay away.
If you can move, run away now.
Run Away
I Won't
I'll come from behind
and hit his knees,
so use that chance
to run away.
Even your eye contact is silly.
なんでアイコンタクトでも馬鹿なんだ
Hanekawa...
羽川先輩
ここらが退きどきかのう!
Perhaps I should take my leave here.
It appears I have been met with serious interference.
どうやら生半(なまなか)ならぬ邪魔が入ったようじゃ
Did I step on the tiger's tail?
虎の尾でも踏んだかのう?
今の拙者ではこれにはとても対処しきれぬわ!
I stand no chance as I am now.
どうやら時機が悪かったと見える
I see this was not my chance after all.
My master is not here either.
我があるじもおらぬようじゃし
I shall return!
ここは出直しじゃ!
You will go home now without detours.
おぬしも寄り道せず
まっすぐおうちに帰るがよかろう!
あの鎧武者は 僕の首を強くつかむことによって
僕の声を吸い取ったのだ
When the armor wrangled my head, it took my voice.
エナジードレイン
Energy drain.
神原のタックルを再現したように
Just as it recreated Kanbaru's tackle,
it recreated my voice.
今は僕の声を 再現した
キスショットと合流したら 伝えておけい!
If you see Kiss-Shot, tell her...
もう少し回復したら 拙者の大事な妖刀
"心渡(こころわたり)" 返してもらいにいくと!
that I will collect my treasured demon sword, Heart Span, once I have recovered.
やはり刀が足りなければ
鎧武者は締まらぬわ!
What is a samurai without his sword?
It has been four hundred years since I lent it to her.
なにせ貸してから四百年でござる
延滞料は覚悟しておくがよかろうとな!
Tell her to prepare for a late fee!
What was that warrior, Araragi?
阿良々木先輩 なんだったんだ?
あの鎧武者は
甲冑が佩刀(はいとう)していないのは
おかしいと思っていたが
I thought it was strange that no sword accompanied the armor, but...
He mentioned the demon sword, Heart Span, and Kiss-Shot...
しかし妖刀"心渡"って 確か
それに キスショットって
Let's worry about that later.
今は 後回しだ それは
Hey, Kanbaru...
神原
Can you jump up to the ceiling from here?
お前なら 助走なしでも ワン...ツーステップくらい で
なんとか天井まで 手が届くんじゃないのか?
よじのぼれるんじゃないのか?
Then climb up?
で 三階から
エレベーターシャフトを通って一階に
Then you can take the elevator shaft down to the first floor—
それはいくらなんでも
後輩を買(か)い被(かぶ)り過ぎだ 阿良々木先輩
You overestimate me, Araragi.
私の脚力は そこまでではない
I'm not that athletic.
Not even I can jump to the ceiling carrying a larger boy.
さすがの私も 年上の男子一人を抱えて
天井まで飛べるほどのジャンプ力はない
そっか
I see.
Araragi.
阿良々木先輩
どうした神原
Yes, Kanbaru?
Will you sleep with me?
私の初めて もらってくれないか
Don't put yourself into the mood!
覚悟を決めるな!
処女のまま死にたくない
I don't want to die a virgin!
This isn't the time for confessions!
カミングアウトをするな
Because you always
say stuff like that
the story you narrated
was on the backburner.
Oh, well.
まあいい
これもまあ 悪い死に様ではあるまい
This isn't such a bad way to die.
阿良々木先輩と共に死ねるなら
望むところだ
Dying together with you is all I wish for.
Uh, sorry.
いや すまん神原
僕 お前に対してそこまでは思えない
I don't feel the same way about you.
え? それは傷つくな
Ouch. That hurts.
僕が共に死にたいと思う相手は ただ一人
There is only one person I want to die together with.
ただ一体の 金髪の怪異だけなのだ
The blonde oddity.
And she isn't here right now.
彼女は今 ここにいない
Therefore we must escape this blazing building.
だからこそ この炎のビルディングから
僕達は生きて 脱出しなければならない
仕方ねえ
All right.
覚悟を決めるしかねえか
Guess it's time to man up.
To do to me what only a man can?
ん? 私の初めてをもらう覚悟をか
そんな大それた覚悟は決められない
I couldn't bring myself to do that.
We can still jump out of a window as a last-ditch effort.
このままここで焼け死ぬよりは
一か八か 窓から飛び降りるしかないだろう
Yeah.
そうだな
I also thought that was our last choice.
私もそれしかないと思っていた
Liar
You were thinking about something
completely different.
Don't get this wrong, Araragi.
The first step is with the right foot.
But since I'm left-handed, I sometimes confuse left and right.
ダイナマイト消火って言うんだよね
こういうのは
This is called Dynamite Firefighting, I believe.
こんなところで死ねると思うな
Don't think you're dying here.
鬼(おに)いちゃんを殺すのはこの僕だ
If anything will kill you, it'll be me.
I hear your laughter near me
You were supposed to be there forever
I breathed onto the classroom window and wrote your name
only to panic and wipe it with my sleeve
I heard your voice from the hallway
and went home in hurry to hide my feelings
At some point I became unable
to talk to you normally
I can hear your laughter a ways away
You were supposed to be next to me forever
You knew how I felt
even when I said nothing
Now I know how important you were to me,
but we will never see each other again